Inventory of the Allen Weinstein papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Washington Quarterly materials
  - UNESCO conference
    - Book inventories, 1982 (Box-folder 47: 4)
    - Notes, 1982 (Box-folder 47: 5)
    - U.S. exhibit, 1982 (Box-folder 47: 6-7)
    - Correspondence, 1982 (Box-folder 47: 8-9)
    - Proceedings, 1982 (Box-folder 47: 10-11)
- Washington Quarterly materials
  - UNESCO conference
    - Proceedings, 1982 (Box-folder 48: 1-2)
    - National Endowment for the Arts, 1982 (Box-folder 48: 3)
    - Correspondence, 1982 (Box-folder 48: 4-5)
- Miscellaneous materials
  - Freedom of Information Act, 1974-1978 (Box-folder 48: 6-9)
  - Corruption study, undated (Box-folder 48: 10)
  - Correspondence, 1978 (Box-folder 48: 11)
  - Serial issue, 1977 (Box-folder 48: 12)
  - Freedom of Information Act, 1974-1978 (Box-folder 49: 1-11)
- Washington Quarterly materials
  - UNESCO conference
    - U.S. exhibit, 1982 (Box-folder 50: 1)
    - Preparations, 1982 (Box-folder 50: 2-3)
    - Clippings, 1982 (Box-folder 50: 4)
  - Memorandum and correspondence, 1982 (Box-folder 50: 5)
- National Endowment for Democracy materials
  - Board of directors meeting, 1983 December 16 (Box-folder 50: 6)
  - Press release, 1983 December 19 (Box-folder 50: 7)
  - Correspondence and report, 1984 (Box-folder 50: 8)
  - Briefing materials, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 50: 9)
  - Clippings, 1983 (Box-folder 50: 10)
  - Clippings, 1983 (Box-folder 51: 1)
  - Correspondence, memoranda, and printed matter, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 51: 2-3)
  - Board meeting, 1984 March 5 (Box-folder 51: 4-7)
  - Clippings, correspondence, and memoranda, 1983 (Box-folder 51: 8-9)
  - Clippings, correspondence, and memoranda, 1983 (Box-folder 52: 1-2)
- The Democracy Program materials
  - Correspondence and memoranda, 1983 (Box-folder 52: 3-4)
  - Mailing list, reports, and statements, 1983 (Box-folder 52: 5)
  - Clippings, correspondence, memoranda, printed matter, and reports, 1983 (Box-folder 52: 6-8)
  - Inter-American Leadership Development, 1983 (Box-folder 52: 9)
  - Venezuela, 1983 (Box-folder 53: 1-2)
  - Task forces, 1983 (Box-folder 53: 3)
  - Current business, 1983 (Box-folder 53: 4-5)
  - Interim report, 1983 April 19 (Box-folder 53: 6)
  - Voice of America interview, 1983 June 16 (Box-folder 53: 7)
  - Alderson Reporting Company, 1983 (Box-folder 53: 8)
  - Clippings, correspondence, memoranda, and reports, 1983 (Box-folder 53: 9-10)
- Research materials, correspondence, and drafts
  - Hiss case, 1937-1977 (Box-folder 54: 1-10)
- Miscellaneous materials
  - Printed matter, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 55: 1)
  - Bahamas, 1986 (Box-folder 55: 2)
  - Memorandum and address list, 1981 (Box-folder 55: 3)
  - Statements, 1986 (Box-folder 55: 4)
  - Paper, 1983 (Box-folder 55: 5)
  - Printed matter, 1983 (Box-folder 55: 6)
- Center for Strategic and International Studies (CSIS) materials
  - International Communications Program, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 56: 1-9)
  - International Communications Program, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 57: 1)
  - Correspondence, memoranda, and reports, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 57: 2-6)
- The Democracy Program materials
  - Correspondence, memoranda, and reports, 1983 (Box-folder 57: 7-8)
  - Paper, 1983 (Box-folder 57: 9)
  - Clippings, 1983 (Box-folder 57: 10)
  - Correspondence, memoranda, and reports, 1983 (Box-folder 58: 1-6)
  - Clippings, 1983 (Box-folder 58: 7)
- National Endowment for Democracy materials
  - Briefing material, 1983 (Box-folder 58: 8)
  - Correspondence, memoranda, and reports, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 58: 9-10)
  - Correspondence, memoranda, printed matter, and reports, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 59: 1-4)
- The Democracy Program materials
  - Correspondence, memoranda, notes, and printed matter, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 59: 5-6)
  - Clippings, 1983 (Box-folder 59: 7)
- Washington Quarterly materials
  - Correspondence, memoranda, and reports, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 59: 8)
  - Clippings, 1982 (Box-folder 59: 9)
  - UNESCO conference, 1982 (Box-folder 59: 10-11)
  - UNESCO conference, 1982 (Box-folder 60: 1)
  - Testimony, 1983 September 29 (Box-folder 60: 2)
  - Call records, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 60: 3)
  - Trips, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 60: 4)
  - Correspondence, memoranda, and reports, 1983 (Box-folder 60: 5-6)
  - Articles and correspondence, 1983 (Box-folder 60: 7-8)
- The Democracy Program materials
  - London-Bonn-Paris trip, 1983 January 22-29 (Box-folder 60: 9)
  - Printed matter, 1982 (Box-folder 60: 10)
  - Report, 1983 November 30 (Box-folder 61: 1)
  - Paper, 1982 September 9 (Box-folder 61: 2)
  - Correspondence, memoranda, and reports, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 61: 3-5)
- National Endowment for Democracy materials
  - Correspondence and reports, 1983 (Box-folder 61: 6)
  - Briefing material, 1983 (Box-folder 61: 7)
- Washington Quarterly materials
  - SmithKline Forum commentary, 1981 (Box-folder 61: 8)
  - Payroll, 1982 (Box-folder 61: 9)
- Washington Quarterly materials
  - Clippings, correspondence, memoranda, and reports, 1982 (Box-folder 62: 1-4)
  - Printed matter, 1982 (Box-folder 62: 5)
- Center for Strategic and International Studies (CSIS) materials
  - Correspondence, memoranda, and reports, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 62: 6-9)
  - Printed matter, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 63: 1)
  - Clippings, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 63: 2-3)
  - Correspondence, memoranda, and reports, 1982 (Box-folder 63: 4)
- Washington Quarterly materials
  - Articles and correspondence, 1983 (Box-folder 63: 5)
  - Correspondence and memoranda, 1983 (Box-folder 63: 6-8)
- Research materials, correspondence, and drafts
  - Typewriter (Hiss case), 1948-1962 (Box-folder 64: 1-3)
  - Magill, A. B., 1949 (Box-folder 64: 4)
  - Marbury, William L., 1948-1949 (Box-folder 64: 5)
  - Matthews, T. S., 1975-1977 (Box-folder 64: 6)
- Writings by Allen Weinstein
  - "The Invention of Richard M. Nixon: The Hiss Case, 1948," typescript, undated (Box-folder 64: 7)
  - Second version of "The Invention,", undated (Box-folder 64: 8)
- Research materials, correspondence, and drafts
  - Nixon, Richard M., 1948-1975 (Box-folder 64: 9-10)
  - Morrow, Felix, 1948-1975 (Box-folder 64: 11)
- The Democracy Program materials
  - Strasbourg Conference on Parliamentary Democracy, 1983 October 4-6 (Box-folder 65: 1)
  - Printed matter, 1980-1982 (Box-folder 65: 2)
- Center for Strategic and International Studies (CSIS) materials
  - International Communications Program, 1983 (Box-folder 65: 3)
  - Report, 1982 (Box-folder 65: 4)
  - Announcements, calendar, and memoranda, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 65: 5)
- Washington Quarterly materials
  - Clippings, 1982 (Box-folder 65: 6)
  - Printed matter, 1983 (Box-folder 65: 7)
  - Articles, correspondence, memoranda, and reports, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 65: 8-11)
  - Papers, 1982 (Box-folder 66: 1-2)
  - Clippings, 1982 (Box-folder 66: 3)
  - Printed matter, 1948-1982 (Box-folder 66: 4)
  - Correspondence, memoranda, and reports, 1982 (Box-folder 66: 5-9)
- Center for Strategic and International Studies (CSIS) materials
  - Budget reports, 1983 (Box-folder 67: 1-2)
  - Cuba, 1983 (Box-folder 67: 3)
  - Consortium for the Study of Intelligence, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 67: 4-5)
- The Democracy Program materials
  - Europe/Tashkent trip, 1983 (Box-folder 67: 6)
  - Printed matter, 1983 (Box-folder 67: 7)
- National Endowment for Democracy materials
  - Urgent business, 1984 (Box-folder 67: 8)
  - Auditing, 1984 (Box-folder 67: 9)
  - Staffing, 1984 (Box-folder 67: 10)
  - Immediate action, 1984 (Box-folder 67: 11)
  - Budget, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 67: 12)
- Center for Strategic and International Studies (CSIS) materials
  - Current members, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 67: 13)
  - Publications, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 67: 14)
  - Handbook, 1982 (Box-folder 67: 15)
  - Photographs, 1983 (Box-folder 67: 16)
  - Meetings, 1982 (Box-folder 68: 1)
  - Standard operating procedures, 1983 (Box-folder 68: 2)
  - Caribbean Basin project, 1981 (Box-folder 68: 3)
  - Urgent business, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 68: 4)
  - Corporate briefing, 1982 June 11 (Box-folder 68: 5)
  - International Communications Program, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 68: 6-7)
  - Printed matter, 1983 (Box-folder 68: 8)
  - Correspondence, memoranda, and reports, 1983 (Box-folder 68: 9-11)
- The Democracy Program materials
  - Correspondence and memoranda, 1983 (Box-folder 68: 12)
  - Biography, 1983 (Box-folder 68: 13)
- Washington Quarterly materials
  - Washington roundtables, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 68: 14)
  - Papers, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 68: 15)
- Writings by Allen Weinstein
  - "A Response to Robert Sherrill," typescript, 1976 (Box-folder 69: 1)
  - Drafts of "A Response" and correspondence, 1976 (Box-folder 69: 2-3)
- Research materials, correspondence, and drafts
  - Josephson, Matthew and Hannah, 1957-1976 (Box-folder 69: 4)
  - Jaffe, Philip J., 1975-1976 (Box-folder 69: 5)
  - Inslerman, Felix August, 1949-1950 (Box-folder 69: 6)
  - Ingram, Horace A., 1948-1949 (Box-folder 69: 7)
  - Lieber, Maxim, 1949-1977 (Box-folder 69: 8-9)
  - Lesser, David, 1974 (Box-folder 69: 10)
  - Lane, Persis and Chester, 1939-1975 (Box-folder 69: 11)
  - Murray, Edith, 1949-1950 (Box-folder 69: 12)
  - Murray, Henry, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 69: 13)
  - Newman, Robert P., 1973-1974 (Box-folder 69: 14)
  - Nicholson, Dr., 1948-1950 (Box-folder 69: 15)
  - Lockwood, Manice, Mr. and Mrs., 1975 (Box-folder 69: 16)
  - Mandel, Ben, 1949 (Box-folder 69: 17)
  - Lovell, Leander, 1949 (Box-folder 69: 18)
  - Lumpkin, Grace, 1948-1976 (Box-folder 69: 19)
  - McCarthy, Elizabeth, 1975 (Box-folder 69: 20)
  - Kohlberg, Alfred, 1946-1949 (Box-folder 69: 21)
  - Murphy, Raymond E., 1945-1949 (Box-folder 69: 22)
  - Nixon, Richard M., 1949-1973 (Box-folder 69: 23)
  - Lovell, Leander, 1949-1950 (Box-folder 70: 1)
  - Kaplan, Irving, 1949-1950 (Box-folder 70: 2)
  - Jones, Cynthia, 1948-1949 (Box-folder 70: 3)
  - Inslerman, Felix August, 1949-1954 (Box-folder 70: 4)
  - Hutchins, Grace, 1948-1953 (Box-folder 70: 5)
  - Massing, Hede and Paul, 1948-1949 (Box-folder 70: 6)
  - Field, Noel and Hermann, 1948-1965 (Box-folder 70: 7-8)
  - Hornbeck, Stanley, 1948-1951 (Box-folder 70: 9)
  - Lane, Chester, 1948-1951 (Box-folder 70: 10)
  - Kaufman, Samuel, 1949-1975 (Box-folder 70: 11)
  - International Juridical Association, 1932-1949 (Box-folder 70: 12)
  - Nelson, Eleanor, 1948-1949 (Box-folder 70: 13)
  - Levine, Isaac Don, 1948-1959 (Box-folder 70: 14)
  - Lieber, Maxim, 1948-1975 (Box-folder 70: 15)
  - Lippmann, Walter, 1948-1975 (Box-folder 70: 16)
  - Van Doren, Mark, 1949 (Box-folder 70: 17)
  - Liebling, A. J., 1949 (Box-folder 70: 18)
  - Lore, Ludwig and Lillian, 1949 (Box-folder 70: 19)
- Washington Quarterly materials
  - Incoming mail, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 71: 1)
  - Correspondence, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 71: 2)
  - Consortium for the Study of Intelligence, 1981 (Box-folder 71: 3)
  - Foreign Policy Association, 1982 (Box-folder 71: 4)
  - Volunteer culture corps, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 71: 5)
  - United States Information Agency, 1983 (Box-folder 71: 6)
  - B'nai B'rith, 1982 (Box-folder 71: 7)
  - Center for Development Policy, 1982 (Box-folder 71: 8)
  - Committee for the Free World, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 71: 9)
  - Committee on the Present Danger, 1981 (Box-folder 71: 10)
  - International Communication Agency, 1982 (Box-folder 71: 11)
- The Democracy Program materials
  - Correspondence, 1983 (Box-folder 71: 12)
  - Printed matter, 1982 (Box-folder 71: 13)
- Miscellaneous materials
  - Infant formula marketing code, 1981 (Box-folder 72: 1)
  - Clippings, 1969-1984 (Box-folder 72: 2)
  - Press release and reports, 1979-1983 (Box-folder 72: 3)
  - Printed matter, 1953-1984 (Box-folder 72: 4-6)
- Washington Quarterly materials
  - Publicity articles, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 72: 7-9)
  - Advertisers, 1979-1981 (Box-folder 73: 1)
  - Printed matter, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 73: 2)
  - Current business, 1982-1984 (Box-folder 73: 3)
  - Reprints, 1981 (Box-folder 73: 4)
  - Accounts, 1984 (Box-folder 73: 5)
  - International Communication Agency, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 73: 6-8)
  - Religion, 1981 (Box-folder 73: 9-10)
- Research materials, correspondence, and drafts
  - Hiss case, 1937-1977 (Box-folder 74: 1-9)
  - Hiss case, 1937-1977 (Box-folder 75: 1-10)
  - Hiss case, 1937-1977 (Box-folder 76: 1-7)
  - Hook, Sidney, 1932-1976 (Box-folder 76: 8)
  - Solow, Herbert, 1948-1949 (Box-folder 76: 9)
  - Freedom of Information Act, 1975-1980 (Box-folder 77: 1)
  - Nixon, Richard M., 1975 (Box-folder 77: 2)
  - Reno, June, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 77: 3)
  - Hiss, Alger, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 77: 4)
- Interview transcripts
  - Hiss, Alger
    - Undated (Box-folder 77: 5)
    - 1975 March 27 (Box-folder 77: 6)
    - 1975 June 21 (Box-folder 77: 7)
    - 1975 October 4 (Box-folder 77: 8)
  - Hiss, Priscilla, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 77: 9)
  - Appell, Donald T., 1974 August 29 (Box-folder 77: 10)
  - Bernard, Viola, 1975 June 23 (Box-folder 77: 11)
  - Burck, Jacob and Esther, 1974 December 30 (Box-folder 77: 12)
  - Cantwell, Robert, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 77: 13)
  - Chambers, John, 1975 August 5 (Box-folder 77: 14)
  - Clubb, O. Edmund, 1975 November 2 (Box-folder 77: 15)
  - Cronin, John, 1975 November 26 (Box-folder 77: 16)
  - Cross, Claude, 1974 July 15 (Box-folder 77: 17)
  - Davis, John F., 1974 August 29 (Box-folder 77: 18)
  - Donegan, Thomas, 1974 November 11 (Box-folder 77: 19)
  - Edwards, Willard, 1975 June 23 (Box-folder 77: 20)
  - Field, Herman, 1975 March 4 (Box-folder 77: 21)
  - Field, Richard, 1974 July 16 (Box-folder 77: 22)
  - Green, Gil, 1974 June (Box-folder 77: 23)
  - Hobson, Timothy, 1974 August 16-17 (Box-folder 77: 24)
  - Hook, Sidney, 1975 April 30 (Box-folder 77: 25)
  - Irons, Peter, 1975 (Box-folder 77: 26)
  - Jaffe, Philip J., 1975 September 17 (Box-folder 77: 27)
  - Josephson, Matthew, 1974 December 9 (Box-folder 77: 28)
  - Lane, Persis, 1975 November 5 (Box-folder 77: 29)
  - Langer, Elinor, 1974 December 28 (Box-folder 77: 30)
  - McCarthy, Elizabeth, 1975 November 19 (Box-folder 77: 31)
  - Marbury, William, 1975 February 24 (Box-folder 77: 32)
  - Massing, Hede, 1974 November 11 (Box-folder 77: 33)
  - Matthews, T. S., 1975 March 22 (Box-folder 77: 34)
  - Morrow, Felix, 1975 May 13 (Box-folder 77: 35)
  - Murray, Henry, 1975 November 4 (Box-folder 77: 36)
  - Peter, Jozsef, 1975 March 20 (Box-folder 77: 37)
  - Schapiro, Meyer and Lillian, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 77: 38)
  - Stripling, Robert, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 77: 39)
  - Tytell family, 1975 November 2 (Box-folder 77: 40)
  - Von Mehren, Robert, 1974 December 11 (Box-folder 77: 41)
  - Welles, S. G., 1975 November 6 (Box-folder 77: 42)
  - Wyzanski, Charles, 1975 April 3 (Box-folder 77: 43)
  - Zabladowsky, David, 1975 November 1 (Box-folder 77: 44)
- Sound recordings (compact sound cassettes)
  - Hiss, Alger, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 78: 1-5)
  - Hiss case, undated (Box-folder 78: 6)
  - Cross, Claude, interview, undated (Box-folder 78: 7-8)
    Access
    Use copy reference number: 2004c61_a_0000634
  - Stripling, Robert, 1975 April 28; 1 sound cassette (Box-folder 78: 9)
    Use copy reference number: 2004c61_a_0009042
  - Krieger, Sam, interview, undated (Box-folder 78: 10-12)
    Use copy reference number: 2004c61_a_0000605
  - Ulanovskya, Nadya, sound recording, 1977 January 4 (Box-folder 78: 13-14)
    Use copy reference number: 2004c61_a_0000609
    Interview and notes on an interview with Nadya Uranovskaya in Jerusalem, Israel.
  - Lieber, Maxim, interview, 1975 May 13 (Box-folder 78: 15)
    Use copy reference number: 2004c61_a_0000599
  - Bernard, Viola, 1975 June 23 (Box-folder 78: 16)
  - Vazzana, Nicholas, sound recording, 1975 June 30 (Box-folder 78: 17)
    Use copy reference number: 2004c61_a_0000606
    Notes on an interview that took place in Colonie, New York, with investigator Nicholas Vazzana.
  - Gannon, Frank, 1975 June; 1 sound cassette (Box-folder 78: 18)
    Use copy reference number: 2004c61_a_0009041
  - Kaplan, Karel, interview and comments by Weinstein, 1977 March 27 - April 19 (Box-folder 78: 19)
    Use copy reference numbers: 2004c61_a_0000603 (comments), 2004c61_a_0000604 (interview)
    The interview with Kaplan is conducted via a translator.
  - Conversation between Allen Weinstein and journalist, undated (Box-folder 78: 20)
- Computer disks (3.5-inch, 2 MB)
  - "The Washington Sources,", undated (Box-folder 78: 21-24)
  - "The Washington Sources," "The Hammers," and "Information on the U.S.,", undated (Box-folder 78: 25)
  - "Information on the U.S.," "Book—17,", undated (Box-folder 78: 26)
  - "Book—14-17, Russian,", undated (Box-folder 78: 27)
  - "Book 17, English,", undated (Box-folder 78: 28)
- Writings by Allen Weinstein
  - Perjury: The Hiss-Chambers Case, London, England, 1978 (Box-folder 79: 1)
  - With Alexander Vassilev, The Haunted Wood: Soviet Espionage in America—The Stalin Era, New York, N.Y., 1999
    - Advance proof (Box-folder 79: 1)
    - Printed copy (Box-folder 79: 2)
- Monographs by others
  - Jowitt, the Earl, The Strange Case of Alger Hiss, 1953 (Box-folder 79: 3)
  - Hiss, Alger, Recollections of a Life, New York, N.Y., 1988 (Box-folder 79: 4)
- Research materials, correspondence, and drafts
  - Photocopies of documents furnished to the FBI by Whittaker Chambers, 1949 (Box-folder 80: 1)
  - Photocopy of statement made by Alger Hiss, 1949 March 8 (Box-folder 80: 2)
  - Photocopies of other documents relating to Alger Hiss, 1948 (Box-folder 80: 3)
  - Synopsis of The Haunted Wood, 1997 (Box-folder 80: 4)
  - "Istochnniki v Vashingtone,", undated (Box-folder 80: 5-6)
    Typescript
  - "Khammery,", undated (Box-folder 80: 7-8)
  - Declassified Russian documents, 1946 (Box-folder 80: 9)
  - "Operations in the U.S.: 1933-1940,", undated (Box-folder 81: 1)
  - Rosenberg, Julius and Ethel
    - 1960-1965 (Box-folder 81: 4-5)
    - 1965-1970 (Box-folder 81: 6-8)
    - 1950-1951 (Box-folder 82: 1-2)
    - 1956-1957 (Box-folder 82: 3-5)
    - 1957-1958 (Box-folder 82: 6)
    - 1957-1958 (Box-folder 83: 1-2)
    - 1953 (Box-folder 83: 3-5)
    - 1954-1956 (Box-folder 83: 6-8)
    - 1970-1974 (Box-folder 84: 1)
    - 1975-1976 (Box-folder 84: 2)
    - 1952-1953 (Box-folder 84: 3)
      Includes letter to Allen Weinstein, 1976.
  - Sobell, Morton
    - 1962-1966 (Box-folder 84: 4-5)
    - 1966 (Box-folder 84: 6-8)
    - 1968-1975 (Box-folder 84: 9)
    - 1966-1967 (Box-folder 85: 1-10)
  - Fuchs, Klaus
    - 1950 (Box-folder 86: 1-11)
    - 1950 (Box-folder 87: 1-8)
    - 1950-1956 (Box-folder 87: 9)
    - 1951-1958 (Box-folder 87: 10)
    - 1958-1966 (Box-folder 87: 11)
    - 1950 (Box-folder 88: 1-12)
    - 1950 (Box-folder 89: 1-3)
    - 1950-1951 (Box-folder 89: 4)
  - Gold, Harry
    - 1950 (Box-folder 89: 5-11)
    - 1951 (Box-folder 90: 1)
  - Brothman, Abraham
    - 1950 (Box-folder 90: 2-7)
    - 1951 (Box-folder 90: 8)
  - Microfilm reels of Bulgarian documents relating to the assassination attempt on Pope John Paul II, 1991
    - Nos. 1-12 (Box-folder 91: 1-12)
    - Nos. 13-25 (Box-folder 92: 1-13)
  - VENONA documents
    - Conference, 1996 October 3-4 (Box-folder 93: 1)
    - National Security Agency, 1995 (Box-folder 93: 2)
    - Miscellaneous documents, 1943-1945 (Box-folder 93: 3-5)
    - Second VENONA Release, 1995 October 12 (Box-folder 93: 6-9)
    - Third VENONA Release, 1996 March
      - Volume 1 (Box-folder 94: 1-2)
      - Volume 2 (Box-folder 94: 3-4)
      - Volume 3 (Box-folder 94: 5-6)
    - Fourth VENONA Release, 1996 July
      - Volume 1 (Box-folder 94: 7)
      - Volume 2 (Box-folder 94: 8-9)
      - Volume 3 (Box-folder 95: 1-2)
      - Volume 4 (Box-folder 95: 3-4)
    - Fifth VENONA Release, 1996 October
      - Volume 1 (Box-folder 95: 5)
      - Volume 2 (Box-folder 95: 6-7)
      - Volume 3 (Box-folder 95: 8)
      - Volume 4 (Box-folder 96: 1-2)
      - Volume 5 (Box-folder 96: 3-4)
      - Volume 6 (Box-folder 96: 5)
      - Volume 7 (Box-folder 96: 6-7)
    - Sixth VENONA Release, 1997 September
      - Volume 1 (Box-folder 96: 8)
      - Volume 2 (Box-folder 96: 9)
    - Conference, 1996 October 3–4 (Box-folder 97: 1-5)
  - "The O.S.S.-NKVD Cooperation," typescript, undated (Box-folder 97: 6)
  - "1941-1945," typescript, undated (Box-folder 97: 7)
  - Neumann, Franz, 2000 (Box-folder 97: 8)
  - "Information on the U.S.," typescript, undated (Box-folder 97: 9-10)
  - "Annexes," typescript, undated (Box-folder 97: 11)
  - "Itshak Akhmerov and 'Pal''s Group," typescript, undated (Box-folder 98: 1)
  - "Martha Dodd and Alfred Stern," typescript, undated (Box-folder 98: 2)
  - "Operations in the U.S.: 1933-40," typescript, undated (Box-folder 98: 4)
  - "The New York Station in the Late 30s," typescript, undated (Box-folder 98: 5)
  - "Golos-Bentley-Browder," typescript, undated (Box-folder 98: 6)
  - "The O.S.S.-NKVD Cooperation," typescript, undated (Box-folder 98: 7)
  - "Introduction," typescript, undated (Box-folder 98: 8)
  - "Operations in the U.S.: 1945-50," typescript, undated (Box-folder 98: 9)
  - Index and translations of Bulgarian documents relating to the assassination attempt on Pope John Paul II, 1991 (Box-folder 98: 10-13)
  - "The Washington Sources," typescript, undated (Box-folder 99: 1-2)
  - "Enormoz," typescript, undated (Box-folder 99: 3-4)
  - "Penetrating the O.S.S.: Moscow and Washington," typescript, undated (Box-folder 99: 5)
  - "Informatsiia po SShA," typescript, undated (Box-folder 99: 6-7)
  - "Operatsii v SShA: 1945-50 gg.," typescript, undated (Box-folder 99: 8)
  - "Gruppa 'Pela' i Itskhakh Akhmerov," typescript, undated (Box-folder 99: 9)
  - "Operatsii v SShA v 1941-45 gg.," typescript, undated (Box-folder 99: 10)
  - "Operatsii v SShA: 1933-40 gg.," typescript, undated (Box-folder 99: 11)
  - "Vvedenie: 'Skelety v shkafu'," typescript, undated (Box-folder 99: 12)
  - "Marta Dodd I Al'fred Stern," typescript, undated (Box-folder 99: 13)
  - "Sostrudnichestvo mezhdu USS I NKVD," typescript, undated (Box-folder 99: 14)
  - "'Zhulik'," typescript, undated (Box-folder 99: 15)
  - "N'iu Iuorkskaia rezidentura v kontse 30-kh godov," typescript, undated (Box-folder 99: 16)
  - "Golos-Bentli-Brauder," typescript, undated (Box-folder 100: 1)
- Writings by Allen Weinstein
  - Introduction to The Haunted Wood, 1998 (Box-folder 100: 2)
  - Final manuscript of The Haunted Wood, 1998 (Box-folder 100: 3-8)
- Research materials, correspondence, and drafts
  - Greenglass, David and Ruth, 1950 (Box-folder 101: 1-4)
  - Silvermaster, Nathan Gregory, 1947-1955 (Box-folder 101: 5)
  - Gold, Harry, 1950 (Box-folder 101: 6-10)
  - Gold, Harry, 1950 (Box-folder 102: 1-4)
  - Sobell, Morton
    - 1941-1950 (Box-folder 102: 5)
    - 1950 (Box-folder 102: 6-9)
    - 1954-1966 (Box-folder 102: 10)
    - 1950 (Box-folder 103: 1-2)
    - 1951-1956 (Box-folder 103: 3-4)
    - 1957-1960 (Box-folder 103: 5-6)
    - 1967-1968 (Box-folder 103: 7-9)
  - Greenglass, David and Ruth
    - 1945-1950 (Box-folder 104: 1-3)
    - 1950 (Box-folder 104: 4)
    - 1950-1953 (Box-folder 104: 5-6)
    - 1953-1957 (Box-folder 104: 7-8)
    - 1957-1961 (Box-folder 104: 9)
  - Miscellaneous documents, 1943-1945 (Box-folder 105: 1)
- Writings by Allen Weinstein
  - Memoranda regarding The Haunted Wood, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 105: 2)
  - Photographs and captions for The Haunted Wood (Box-folder 105: 3-5)
- Research materials, correspondence, and drafts
  - Sobell, Morton
    - 1951 (Box-folder 105: 6-7)
    - 1950-1953 (Box-folder 105: 8-9)
    - 1954-1956 (Box-folder 105: 10)
    - 1950-1956 (Box-folder 106: 1-5)
    - 1956-1957 (Box-folder 106: 6-8)
    - 1950 (Box-folder 107: 1-2)
    - 1951 (Box-folder 107: 3-4)
    - 1953-1954 (Box-folder 107: 5-7)
    - 1956 (Box-folder 107: 8-9)
- Writings by Allen Weinstein
  - The Haunted Wood, typescript, 1997 (Box-folder 108: 1-9)
  - Perjury, proofs of new edition, 1997 (Box-folder 108: 10)
  - The Haunted Wood, typescript, 1997 (Box-folder 109: 1-12)